# Benjamen R. ("Randy") King

# Full-Stack Web Developer

benjamen.rk@gmail.com 5015 E Ustick Rd No 127 Caldwell, ID 83605-6814 (208) 590-8443

Website: <a href="https://brandallk.github.io/">https://brandallk.github.io/</a>

Github: <a href="https://github.com/brandallk">https://github.com/brandallk</a>

#### **ABOUT ME**

My background in hard science research taught me to face and overcome technical challenges while working closely with collaborators. My decade of hard-knocks experience as an entrepreneur taught me to embrace organized planning and take final responsibility for outcomes. I bring that experience, and a life-long love of learning, to my pursuit of excellence creating software.

### **SKILLS & TRAINING**

- JavaScript
- Node / Express
- Vue / Vuex
- MongoDB
- Mocha / Chai
- jQuery

- C# / .NET
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Sass / SCSS
- Bootstrap
  - Git / Github
- PHP
- Laravel 5
- Eloquent ORM
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- PHPUnit

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Boise CodeWorks (Boise, ID) - Student

January 2018 - PRESENT

- Gained intensive experience building projects with JavaScript, C#, frameworks, and full-stack concepts.
- Worked in Agile-inspired teams to manage and meet project goals.

#### **E&L Custom Ag (Idaho / Nevada)** - Partner/Entrepreneur

November 2009 - January 2018

- Used self-taught web-dev skills to launch a company services website & ecommerce sales platform built with PHP and JavaScript.
- Used organic science experience to help build & sustain crop production covering thousands of acres in a multi-state operation.

**University of Colorado Boulder, Chemistry Dept.** - Research & Teaching Fellow

August 2006 - November 2009

- Performed original research in organic chemistry while a PhD candidate.
- Won department's 'Graduate Teaching Excellence Award' three times.

## **EDUCATION**

The College of Idaho, Caldwell, ID - B.S. in Chemistry

August 1999 - March 2003

My studies included multiple semesters of mathematics (e.g. multivariable calculus, differential equations) and courses in Visual Basic and C++. While earning my degree, I also completed a research internship at the University of Syracuse, NY.